<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>development on Yet another tech blog</title><link>https://trebaud.github.io/tags/development/</link><description>Recent content in development on Yet another tech blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 07 Feb 2019 00:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://trebaud.github.io/tags/development/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>My dev setup</title><link>https://trebaud.github.io/posts/dev-config/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Feb 2019 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://trebaud.github.io/posts/dev-config/</guid><description>In this post I list all the programs and configurations I use for my development workflow. I favor a terminal centric approach in the tools I use as I consider it to be the most efficient way to work.
Tools Code editor: Neovim with vim-plug Shell: fish with oh-my-fish and spacefish Terminal emulator: kitty tig Optional Command line finder: fzf Command line color scheme: Gogh Vim browser extension: Vimium Alternatives Tmux Github-desktop Vscode i3 zsh with oh-my-zsh and spaceship theme Configuration Here you can find the different configuration files I use for the various tools listed above.</description></item><item><title>Implementing a Merkle tree in Python</title><link>https://trebaud.github.io/posts/merkle-tree/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Jan 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://trebaud.github.io/posts/merkle-tree/</guid><description>Unless you&amp;rsquo;ve been living under a rock for the past few years you have probably heard of Bitcoin, the decentralized, peer-to-peer, public, trustless, cash system protocol. Regardless of whether or not you think bitcoin&amp;rsquo;s current valuation is in a bubble or worse that it&amp;rsquo;s a Ponzi scheme, it&amp;rsquo;s undeniable that the protocol solves a real and old problem in distributed computing, a.k.a the Byzantine&amp;rsquo;s General Problem. One of the underlying data structures ensuring the immutability of the blockchain is the Merkle tree.</description></item></channel></rss>